A Guide to the Papers of the McDowell Family, 2969
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the McDowell Family 1700, 1831-1917
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
2969
This collection consists of ca. 375 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was loaned to the Library by C. Venable Minor of Charlottesville, Virginia, on June 2, 1948.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of correspondence and papers, 1802-1895, ca. 375 items, relating to the McDowell, Preston and Miller families. Correspondence and papers chiefly relate to the family of James and Susanna Smith (Preston) McDowell and their children, particularly Sally Campbell Preston (McDowell) Miller. There is much correspondence and papers relating to the divorce of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas.
Contents List
- Correspondence and Papers of the McDowell-Preston-Miller Families
  - Thomas Hart Benton and Elizabeth McDowell Benton to Sally Campbell Preston McDowell 1837-1851
  - Moses D. Hoge to Sally Campbell Preston (McDowell) Miller 1872-1895
  - Sally Campbell Preston McDowell to her parents, James and Susanna Smith Preston McDowell 1836
  - Sally Campbell Preston McDowell to her parents, James and Susanna Smith Preston McDowell 1837-1846
  - Susanna Smith Preston McDowell to her daughter, Sally Campbell Preston McDowell [1840s]
  - Thomas Preston McDowell to his wife, Constance Warwick McDowell 1862-1865
  - Mary Miller to her brother, John Miller, and related 1865-1875
  - Charles S. Venable to his sister-in-law and brother-in-law, Sally Campbell Preston (McDowell) and John Miller 1867-1894
  - Correspondence between Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and her husband, John Miller 1861-1885
  - Correspondence of Sally Campbell Preston (McDowell) Miller and John Miller 1851-1885
  - Correspondence of the McDowell and related families 1802, 1837-1871, n.d.
  - Letters to Col. James McDowell 1820-1835
  - Letters to James McDowell 1834-1847
  - Letters to Sally Campbell Preston McDowell 1839-1866
  - Letters to Sally Campbell Preston (McDowell) Miller from her brothers and sister 1842-1860
  - Letters to Sally Campbell Preston (McDowell) Miller from uncles, aunts, and cousins 1836-1892
  - Letters to Susanna Smith Preston McDowell 1843-1847
  - Papers of the McDowell and related families 1833-1895
- Correspondence and Papers relating to the Marriage and Divorce of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas
  - Correspondence relating to the Marriage of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas 1839-1844, (numbered 1-30)
  - Correspondence relating to the Marriage of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas 1845, (numbered 31-56)
  - Correspondence relating to the Divorce of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas 1846 Jan-June, (numbered 57-81)
  - Correspondence relating to the Divorce of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas 1846 July-Dec, (numbered 82-111)
  - Correspondence relating to the Divorce of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas 1847-1851, n.d., (numbered 112-142)
  - Papers relating to the Divorce of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas 1843-1847
  - Papers relating to the Divorce of Sally Campbell Preston McDowell and Francis Thomas n.d.